Guide to the Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1930-1992; Series I; 33.83; (106 boxes)
  - Slides
    - Housed in Slide Boxes
      - Other Slides
        - Luke, Hommocks Road, 1988 August (Box 89)
        - Larchmont: Fuji Tests 1, 400 and 800 ASA, 1992 August (Box 89)
        - Color slides of "More than Meets The Eye" of "The Violent Peace," of "Carl Mydans Photojournalist", undated (Box 89)
        - Photolab people: Tests, "Lumiquest" reflector, 35mm with "283" on Fuji 100 at 200, 1992 August 29 (Box 89)
        - Carl Mydans, Vietnam at TET, undated (Box 89)
        - Time Covers, undated (Box 89)
        - Projection Slides, 1997 January; (4 slide boxes) (Box 89)
        - Ralph Morse: Walk around multiple flash in school room (for technique lecture), undated (Box 89)
        - Kelly Johnson, projection slides for lecture, undated (Box 89)
        - Slides for U-2 chapter, undated (Box 89)
        - Slides from newly chosen pictures, undated; (11 slide boxes) (Box 89)
        - Retrospective slides returned by Crocker Art Museum, 1987 (Box 89)
        - Carl Mydans: tests made of and odds and ends at Time Inc and elsewhere, 1980 (Box 89)
        - Carl Mydans tests. Several prints made. Poor images., 1984 (Box 89)
        - Time Inc. Photolab tests, 1986 January (Box 89)
        - Time Inc. tests (darkrooms) with Vivitar 3700, 1987 June (Box 89)
        - Fuji 100 and 200 tests; Eisie, Debbie Cohen, Jean Wong, Christine Balacarse, Cindy Joyce, Carl Mydans, and Tom Stone, 1988 February 24 (Box 89)
        - Carl -- tests by Mel Levine Office with Kathie Doak, 1988 July 19 (Box 89)
        - Color: Printed Frames (By Paul), 1982 December (Box 89)
    - Housed in Sleeves
      - Easter Island, undated; 5 (Box 90)
      - Yugoslavia, circa 1963; 3 (Box 90)
      - Sturgeon, undated (Box 90)
      - Dew Line, undated (Box 90)
      - Yucatán-Nassau, 2 (Box 90)
      - Tristan da Cunha, 1963; 3 (Box 90)
      - Privatization of Russian Farms, 1992 (Box 90)
      - National Geographic Seminar and Japan/Japan Book, undated (Box 90)
      - Captions and slugs for John Durniak's presentation of these slides at Steamboat Springs, Colorado, 1991 July (Box 90)
      - San Francisco, 1979 (Box 90)
      - Langkawi, Malaysia, 1983 (Box 90)
      - Religion in the Soviet Union, Billy Graham, Russia, 1984; 2 (Box 90)
      - Three slides for Barnstorm projection, 1997 October 3 (Box 90)
      - Zihuatanejo, Ixtapa, 1979 (Box 90)
      - Puerto Vallarta (Box 90)
      - Las Hadas (Box 90)
      - Acapulco (Box 90)
      - China: The Early Years, 1941 (Box 90)
      - Venezuela, undated; 3 (Box 90)
      - Nha Trang, Vietnam (Box 90)
      - A Tale of Two Williams, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, 1977 (Box 90)
      - Unidentified (Box 90)
      - Joseph P. Lash (Box 90)
      - President Aquino and Jaime Ongpin, Philippines, 1987 (Box 90)
      - Various slides (Box 90)
        Includes slides of United Nations, Moorea, Acapulco, Majuro (Micronesia), pheasant, palm oil, Tristan de Cunha, and London (England).
      - Portraits photographed for Black Star, 4 (Box 90)
        Includes slides of Theodore White, John D. MacDonald, Andy Rooney, David Halberstam, William Paley, Lester Bernstein, Emily Hahn, Richard Salant, William Schuman, Grant Tinker, Walter Cronkite, Michael Kinsley, Eisie, Edward K. Thompson, Lee Kuan Yew, Ray Brady, Jack Rosenthal, Arthur Gelb, Barbara Howar, Charles Hamilton, Craig Claiborne, Patricia Neal, Gene Jankowski, William Kennedy, Morris Church, Harrison Salisbury, Roberto Goizueta, Van Gordon Sauter, Laurence Tisch, Dan Rather, General MacArthur, and others.
      - Portraits and places photographed for Black Star, 2 (Box 90)
        Includes slides of Queen Elizabeth II in Nigeria, John Huston, Philippines politicians, Angkor Wat, east Africa, Thailand, Burma, Micronesia, Portugal, and England.
      - Big Four -- Geneva (Box 91)
      - A Tale of Two Williams, 1977-1982 (Box 91)
        Includes copy of publication, A Tale of Two Williams, and slides.
      - Burmese Dance (Box 91)
      - India, Kashmir, Nepal, 1974 (Box 91)
      - Easter Island and Bird Island (Box 91)
      - Old Age (Box 91)
      - Saigon, 1950 March (Box 91)
      - San Francisco, 1979 (Box 91)
      - Sri Lanka, 1975 (Box 91)
      - Eisenhowers and Khrushchevs, 1959 (Box 91)
      - West Indies, Caribbean islands, and South Seas (Box 91)
      - Herbert Morrison, Clement Attlee, and Hugh Gaitskell, 1955 May (Box 91)
      - Archbishop Makarious (Box 91)
      - Indian Point Power Plant (Box 91)
      - Japan (Box 91)
      - Korea, 2 (Box 91)
      - London underground (Box 91)
      - Malaysia (Box 91)
      - Election Night at NBC, 1980 (Box 91)
      - Moscow (Box 91)
      - Christmas in Albany, 1979 (Box 91)
      - NYC scenes (Box 91)
      - Governor Jerry Brown, 1976 (Box 91)
      - Winston Churchill, 1955 (Box 91)
      - Sir James Goldsmith, 1988 (Box 91)
      - Leatherback Turtles (Box 91)
      - John Hersey (Box 91)
      - Al Hirschfeld (Box 91)
      - Henry Kissinger and family (Box 91)
      - Khrushchev, 1960 (Box 91)
      - Walter Lippmann, 1964 (Box 91)
      - Thomas Mann (Box 91)
      - Imelda and Ferdinand Marcos and Marcos in Hawaii, 1987; 2 (Box 91)
      - William Seawell, 1980 (Box 91)
      - Patrick Steptoe, 1979 (Box 91)
      - Judge Harold Tyler, 1980 (Box 91)
      - Kurt Waldheim, 1977 (Box 91)
      - Xeroxes of Black Star pictures and captions for Carl Mydans set on personalities (Box 91)
      - Orangutans; slides and text for Smithsonian article, 1973 (Box 91)
      - Roy Rowan (Box 91)
      - Perez de Cuellar, Secretary General of the U.N., 1988 (Box 91)
      - Malacca, Malaysia (Box 91)
      - Russia, including text for "Winter in Moscow" (Box 91)
      - Malaysia, Singapore, Thailand, Indonesia, and Mexico, 2 (Box 92)
      - Tristan da Cunha (Box 92)
        Includes article "Far-off Exiles of Tristan."
      - Slides of published articles "Atom Bomb Island" and "Return to Bikini" (Box 92)
      - Slides used during Sprague Award Presentation, 1986 July 11-12 (Box 92)
      - Gloucester: Day-In-The-Life, 1959 (Box 92)
      - ICP Projection slides for June 5 dinner and honors, 1992 (Box 92)
      - Leatherback Turtles, Terengganu, Malaysia, 1974 (Box 92)
      - Turkey, 1983 (Box 92)
      - Viet Nam, Cam Ranh Bay, 1968 (Box 92)
      - Tokyo Scenes for N.H.K. Year-End program called "Portrait Japan" (slides and negatives), 1989 December; 2 (Box 92)
      - Lien Ying-Cho (George Lien), Singapore, 1970 (Box 92)
      - Jimmy Carter / Plains and Archery, Georgia, 1976; 4 (Box 92)
        Includes contacts.
      - East Africa wildlife and Japan rice harvest, 1975-1984; 2 (Box 93)
      - Singapore, 3 (Box 93)
      - Desert Tracks, General Patton (Box 93)
      - China, 1971 (Box 93)
      - Philippines Elections, 1986 (Box 93)
      - Along the Volga, 1960 (Box 93)
    - Original labels for boxes of slides (Box 94)
  - Negatives
    - Japan occupation (personal) (Box 95)
    - Japan occupation (personal) (Box 96)
    - Japan occupation (personal) (Box 97)
    - [miscellaneous] (Box 98)
    - [miscellaneous], 1930-1949 (Box 99)
      Includes negatives of Japan, Wentworth, New Hampshire, cotton cultivation in Mississippi, portraits of Hollywood personalities.
    - [miscellaneous] (Box 100)
      Includes negatives of Hong Kong, portraits, Philippines, Tahiti, Cuban Missile crisis, etc.
    - Early historic, Time Inc. and Friends, Hollywood Period (Box 101)
    - Early historic, Time Inc. and Friends, Hollywood Period (Box 102)
    - Early historic, Time Inc. and Friends, Hollywood Period (Box 103)
    - Early historic, Time Inc. and Friends, Hollywood Period (Box 104)
    - Contacts and negatives of photographs made through the early years for SOLO (Box 105)
    - Personal (Box 106)
- Subject Files, 1942-2000; Series II; 35.42; (35 boxes)
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  The series contains clippings, printed material, and research notes pertaining to Carl and Shelley Smith Mydans' work and research interests dating from 1942 to 2000.
  - Mydans bibliography, undated (Box 107)
  - Yokohama Exhibition -- Retrospective Exhibition -- Tokyo, 1986 (Box 107)
  - December 7: The First Thirty Hours, 1942 (Box 107)
  - Japan--NHK, 1989 (Box 107)
  - Kay Tateishi and Frank Iwama, 1976-1990 (Box 107)
  - Shinano (Japan) (Box 107)
  - Nikkor Club--Jun Miki, 1982-1992 (Box 107)
  - Japan suggestions (Box 107)
  - Japan: Behavior (Box 107)
  - War Crimes Trials (International Military Tribune of the Far East) (Box 107)
  - Text piece--Japan, self-image. "Center Stage with a Brand New Script". LIFE International., 1970 (Box 107)
  - Japan (Box 107)
  - Dependent housing--occupation years, 1947 (Box 107)
  - Royal Arch Gunnison's "So Sorry, No Peace" (Box 107)
  - Bill and Mary Carty--Australia and The Occupation, 1993 (Box 107)
  - MacArthur: Cineworld film series: American Caesar, 1982-1984 (Box 107)
  - MacArthur: Merle Miller's Truman's talk of Kay Summersby (Box 107)
  - Hoff, Earl M. Memoirs. (Box 107)
  - Julian Bach, 1975 (Box 107)
  - Elna Wilkinson, 1979-1983 (Box 107)
  - My book given to...and changing costs of the book... (Box 107)
  - TIME: published pictures (Box 107)
  - Money (magazine), 1996 (Box 107)
  - Sports Illustrated, 1984-1997 (Box 107)
  - Louis Kraar (Box 107)
  - Cameras and technical data (Box 107)
  - Book of the Month Club--TIME Inc. Books (Box 107)
  - William Shirer (Box 107)
  - Photo equipment and film (Box 107)
  - Fortune (magazine) (Box 107)
  - People (magazine), 1974-1995 (Box 108)
  - Captions--Burma Dance (Box 108)
  - Entertainment Weekly, 1990 (Box 108)
  - Eddie Adams Workshop, 1990 (Box 108)
  - Flicky Ford, 1989 (Box 108)
  - Trompe l'Oeil Paintings, 1984 (Box 108)
  - Overseas Press Club, 1989-1990 (Box 108)
  - Joe Schilling/28th Floor Exhibition, 1985 (Box 108)
  - United Nations, 1988-1989 (Box 108)
  - Picture Agencies, 1987 (Box 108)
  - American Photographer (magazine), 1989 (Box 108)
  - New York Times (Box 108)
  - Laurence Tisch (and CBS), 1986-1987 (Box 108)
  - ABC, 1986 (Box 108)
  - NBC, 1980-1988 (Box 108)
  - Picture agencies (stock photos) (Box 108)
  - Stock pictures (Box 108)
  - Money (magazine), 1980 (Box 108)
  - GEO, 1978 (Box 108)
  - LIFE: The Second Decade (Box 108)
  - Leica (Box 108)
  - Minolta (Box 108)
  - Vivitar (Box 108)
  - American Photographer--Ron Bailey, 1985 (Box 108)
  - Camera--office folder (Box 108)
  - Pending office folder (Box 108)
  - TIME picture syndication (Box 108)
  - TIME, 1994 (Box 108)
  - Eastman Kodak (Box 108)
  - Constitution (magazine) (Box 108)
  - LIFE suggestions (Box 108)
  - LIFE (Box 108)
  - Catalog project for TIME, Inc. (Box 108)
  - Carl and Shelley Mydans: biographies (Box 108)
  - Nikon and Nippon Kogaku (Box 108)
  - Sprague Award (Box 108)
  - Teddy White (Box 108)
  - Ed Whitcomb (Box 108)
  - Hansel Mieth and Nancy Schiesari, 1996 (Box 108)
  - Domke, 1988 (Box 108)
  - References and research and checking points for the Abrams picture book (Box 108)
  - Exhibition and book correspondence answered (or decided not to be answered.), 1986 (Box 108)
  - Story suggestions (Box 108)
  - Alfred Eisenstaedt, 1989-1996 (Box 108)
  - Eisie: quotes and references for Linden Gross, 1996 (Box 108)
  - Life photographers, 1999 (Box 109)
  - Life photographers, 1966-1995 (Box 109)
  - LIFE, 1973-1995 (Box 109)
  - Dave Scherman, 1997 (Box 109)
  - Peter Stackpole, 1988-1997 (Box 109)
  - George Silk (New Guinea book) (Box 109)
  - Nick Ut, 1996 (Box 109)
  - Bill Pierce (Box 109)
  - Rex Hardy, 1986 (Box 109)
  - Philippe Halsman, 1973-1979 (Box 109)
  - Yousuf Karsh, 1976-1988 (Box 109)
  - Henry Cartier-Bresson, 1968-1995 (Box 109)
  - John Phillips (Charles-Henri Favrod), Director, Musée de l'Elysée, Lausanne, 1990 (Box 109)
  - David Hume Kennerly, 1979 (Box 109)
  - Larry Burrows and John Starr, 1971-1995 (Box 109)
  - Dmitri Kessel, 1985-1994 (Box 109)
  - Fred Conrad, 1988-1992 (Box 109)
  - Gjon Mili, 1988-1995 (Box 109)
  - Arthur Rothstein, 1977-1997 (Box 109)
  - Slim Aarons (Box 109)
  - Fritz Goro, 1979-1988 (Box 109)
  - Ralph Morse (Box 109)
  - Leonard McCombs, 1951-1955 (Box 109)
  - Christopher Morris, 1994 (Box 109)
  - Howard Sochurek, 1994 (Box 109)
  - Bill Eppridge, 1988 (Box 109)
  - George Thames, 1986-1994 (Box 109)
  - Heinz Kluetmeier, 1996 (Box 109)
  - Margaret Bourke-White (memoir), 1971-1992 (Box 109)
  - International Center of Photography, 1986-1995 (Box 109)
  - Edward Meel and Dirck Halstead--Media Management Service, Veterans of LIFE Project, 1987-1995 (Box 109)
  - Robert Capa, 1954-1985 (Box 109)
  - Color (Box 109)
  - Richard Avedon, 1978-1994 (Box 109)
  - Myron Davis, 1993 (Box 109)
  - Mary Ellen Mark (Box 109)
  - Neil Leifer (Box 109)
  - Michael Williamson and Dale Maharidge--"And Their Children After Them"--And the Sacramento Bee and other things Sacramento, 1988-1996 (Box 109)
  - Rotkin Review, 1992 (Box 109)
  - Eugene Smith, 1980-1994 (Box 109)
  - Walker Evans (Box 109)
  - Ben Shahn, 1968-1984 (Box 109)
  - Edward Steichen, 1966-1994 (Box 109)
  - Bill and Cary Vaughn Foley, 1985-1997 (Box 109)
  - Newsreel Wong, 1972 (Box 109)
  - Gordon Parks, 1967-1986 (Box 109)
  - John Faber and Photojournalism (The National Press Photographers Association) (Box 109)
  - Dirck Halstead, 1982-1997 (Box 109)
  - Anthony Suau--Russian FSA story, 1992 (Box 109)
  - Stefan Lorant (Box 110)
  - Hansel Mieth and Otto Hagel, 1994 (Box 110)
  - ICP 1992 Infinity Awards--Lifetime Achievement, 1992-1996 (Box 110)
  - Veterans of Life--Video transcript--Dirck Halstead and Ed Meell, 1987 (Box 110)
  - David Douglas Duncan, 1974-1996 (Box 110)
  - Ed and Joyce Clark, 1992 (Box 110)
  - Marguerite Higgins, 1987 (Box 110)
  - Barbara Cox, 1997 (Box 110)
  - Barbara Cox--The San Diego Exhibition, 1995-1998 (Box 110)
  - Grace and George Schaub (Box 110)
  - Clare Boothe Luce, 1981-1982 (Box 110)
  - Henry Luce: 1985 Hall of Fame, Folio Publishing Corporation (Box 110)
  - Luce and Clare (Box 110)
  - Joe Rosenthal, 1995 (Box 110)
  - Lillian Fuentes and Linda Faulhaber, 1993-1995 (Box 110)
  - Debra Cohen, 1992 (Box 110)
  - Cosden/Chickering (Box 110)
  - Edward McCreary--Santo Tomas and ingathering, 1999 (Box 110)
  - Yukiko Launois, 1997 (Box 110)
  - The Constitution--Pat Roach and Rudolph Rauch, 1991-1995 (Box 110)
  - Rudolph (Ru) Rauch--Constitution, 1993-1994 (Box 110)
  - Tom and Helen Lambert, 1992-1995 (Box 110)
  - Crocker Art Museum, Sacramento, 1986-1990 (Box 110)
  - Luce and Molly Thompson, 1992-1995 (Box 110)
  - University of Missouri, 1998 (Box 110)
  - Kathy Ryan, 1995 (Box 110)
  - Bernie Clayton, Hoff, and Indiana University, 1995-1997 (Box 110)
  - Frank Gibney, 1992-1994 (Box 110)
  - The Ryders, 1982-1989 (Box 110)
  - Susan Moeller (Compassion Fatigue 1998) (Box 110)
  - Susan Moeller: Two Chapters--War Photography, 1986-1988 (Box 110)
  - Books: Whiteside series of three on publishing, 1979-1996 (Box 110)
  - Architecture, 1979 (Box 110)
  - Archeology, ancient lore, 1970-1982 (Box 110)
  - Art--painting, sculpture, design (Box 110)
  - Auctions, 1993-1996 (Box 110)
  - Autographs (Box 110)
  - Last words and greetings (Box 110)
  - Bicycles and mopeds (Box 110)
  - Adventure/professions/hobbies (Box 110)
  - Aircraft, aerospace, airlines, pilots, armaments, airline VIP cards (Box 110)
  - Americans abroad (Box 110)
  - Air raid shelters (Box 110)
  - AIDS (Box 110)
  - Advertising and public relations (Box 110)
  - Anthropology (Box 110)
  - Behavior (Box 111)
  - Obituaries (Box 111)
  - Stupidity and fate which conspires against crime (Box 111)
  - Macabre; turn of fate; the spirit of the odd (Box 111)
  - Blacks (Box 111)
  - Black sheep: the stainers of the family image (Box 111)
  - Britain, Ireland (Box 111)
  - Cable TV (Box 111)
  - Cannibalism (Box 111)
  - Cartoons (Box 111)
  - Cities and urban developments and security (Box 111)
  - Christmas (Box 111)
  - Communism/socialism (Box 111)
  - Communications--information society (Box 111)
  - Computers/word processing (Box 111)
  - Corruption/wheelers and dealers (buying and selling gold, etc), money lenders (Box 111)
  - Cowboy (Box 111)
  - Crime and criminals, security (Box 111)
  - Cults (Box 111)
  - Culture, dance, show business (Box 111)
  - Diplomatic service (Box 111)
  - Drugs (Box 111)
  - Deserts (Box 111)
  - Disasters (Box 111)
  - Industry, economics and finance, labor (Box 111)
  - Earthquakes (Box 111)
  - Education (Box 111)
  - Earth (Box 111)
  - Energy--power (Box 111)
  - Fatal rides: ferries, buses, etc. (Box 111)
  - Fiction (Box 111)
  - Food (Box 111)
  - Frauds and forgeries (Box 111)
  - Films, cinema, Hollywood, show business (Box 111)
  - Funding (Box 111)
  - Gardening, forests (Box 111)
  - Gambling/lottery (Box 111)
  - Geology (Box 111)
  - Gold and gems, jade (Box 111)
  - Kent State: Creative Arts Festival (April 16-21 1972) (Box 111)
  - Graffiti (Box 111)
  - Gypsies (Box 111)
  - Hijacking (Box 111)
  - Homesteading (Box 111)
  - Hostages (Box 112)
  - Housing--real estate (Box 112)
  - Human rights (Box 112)
  - Insects and bugs (Box 112)
  - Immigration (Box 112)
  - Jews (Box 112)
  - Journalism--samples and illustrations (Box 112)
  - Labor (Box 112)
  - Law and the professions (Box 112)
  - Leprosy (Box 112)
  - Lefthandedness (Box 112)
  - Libraries (Box 112)
  - Metric system (Box 112)
  - Modeling (Box 112)
  - Music (Box 112)
  - International trends and conflicts (Box 112)
  - NATO (Box 112)
  - Nuclear power and other forms of power (Box 112)
  - Napoleon (Box 112)
  - Old age--senior citizens (Box 112)
  - Islands (Box 112)
  - Natural products: olive oil, cork, spices, herbs, etc. (Box 112)
  - Oceans, rivers, wetlands, water (Box 112)
  - Oil in Asia and the Pacific (Box 112)
  - Oil (Box 112)
  - Authors, agents, writing, publishers, and contracts (Box 112)
  - Press (Box 112)
  - Politics and government (Box 112)
  - Profiles, close-ups (Box 112)
  - Population, immigration (Box 112)
  - Post offices (Box 112)
  - Pottery, ceramics (Box 112)
  - Pirates (Box 112)
  - Raw materials, coal, etc. (Box 112)
  - Railroads (Box 112)
  - Real estate (Box 112)
  - Religion (Box 112)
  - Retirement, aging (Box 112)
  - Ships/boats/men of the sea (Box 112)
  - O.J. Simpson (Box 112)
  - Space (Box 112)
  - Showa Maru and Oil Tanker Spills (Box 112)
  - Sports, also sports and violence (Box 112)
  - Suburbia (Box 112)
  - Suicide (Box 112)
  - Tattoo (Box 112)
  - Technology (Box 112)
  - Television (Box 112)
  - Terrorism (Box 112)
  - Theatre (Box 113)
  - Time/Clocks/Watches (Box 113)
  - Tradition (Box 113)
  - Typewriters (Box 113)
  - U.S. Customs--photo equipment registrations (Box 113)
  - Transportation (Box 113)
  - Universities/colleges, Stanford (Box 113)
  - U.S. policy (Box 113)
  - United Nations (Box 113)
  - Waste, garbage, community dumps (Box 113)
  - Weather (Box 113)
  - Watergate (Box 113)
  - Wilderness / Primitive People (Box 113)
  - Witchcraft, black magic, omens, tradition signs, the evil eye (Box 113)
  - Youth and education (Box 113)
  - Waterpower (Box 113)
  - X-ray (Box 113)
  - Coming world anarchy, Third World/North-South World conflict, 20th century (Box 113)
  - Women, women's lib, sex, women in war (Box 113)
  - Travel, Lindblad: booklets and tours (Box 113)
  - Travel (Box 113)
  - Animals and wildlife (Box 113)
  - Animals/birds, endangered (Box 113)
  - Invaders (Box 113)
  - Bamboo (Box 113)
  - Birds: photographing them (Box 113)
  - Birds and bird watching (Box 113)
  - Cactus (Box 113)
  - Sarajevo--AmeriCares, Dec. 1993 (Box 113)
  - Cattle (Box 113)
  - Chickens (Box 113)
  - Cork (Box 113)
  - Cork, Olives (Box 113)
  - Cotton, grain, corn, rice, cereals, soybeans, fishmeal (Box 113)
  - Crows (Box 113)
  - Gardening, fruit & vegetables (Box 113)
  - Farming; "See protein grains folder" (Box 114)
  - Mushrooms: ginseng and truffles (Box 114)
  - Gulls (Box 114)
  - Hogs (Box 114)
  - Horses, mules (Box 114)
  - Locusts, cicadas, katydids (Box 114)
  - Pandas (Box 114)
  - Potatoes (Box 114)
  - Rats, mice (Box 114)
  - Rubber, tin, cocoa, pepper, spices, sugar (Box 114)
  - Spices / Spice Islands (Box 114)
  - Snails (Box 114)
  - Squirrels (Box 114)
  - Spiders (Box 114)
  - Sunflowers (Box 114)
  - Stanford (Box 114)
  - Tomatoes (Box 114)
  - Wasps (Box 114)
  - Worms (Box 114)
  - Zoos (Box 114)
  - Wilderness (Box 114)
  - Japan, 1969 (Box 114)
  - Fire--Japan (Box 114)
  - Press: Japan--books, authors (Box 114)
  - Eta, Koreans, minority groups, foreigners (Box 114)
  - Japan: customs and traditions (Box 114)
  - Japan: personalities and close-ups (Box 114)
  - Japan: fishing and sea resources, oceanography (Box 114)
  - Japan: bases, rearmament, National Defense Force (Box 114)
  - Japan: foods and restaurants (Box 114)
  - Japan: youth and student unrest and demonstrations, universities/schools (Box 114)
  - Japan: sports, health, games, fun activities (Box 114)
  - Japan: crime (Box 114)
  - Japan: farming, rice (Box 114)
  - Japan:TIME's cover file, Tokyo 1970 (Box 114)
  - Japanese in Southeast Asia and aid (Box 114)
  - Japan: business and economics, foreign aid, her miracle (Box 114)
  - Japan: Expo 1970 (Box 114)
  - Ishiyamas--Japan (Box 114)
  - Japan: expense accounts, entertainment, graft, taxes, travel, tourism (Box 114)
  - Japan: ships and shipping (Box 114)
  - Japan: environment (Box 114)
  - Japan: Soviet-held Kurils (Box 114)
  - Japan: Okinawa, Bonins, the 1970 question (Box 114)
  - Japan: Tsuji (Box 114)
  - Japan: Geisha and Yoshiwara (Box 114)
  - Japan, 1995 (Box 114)
  - Japan: picture suggestions (Box 114)
  - Japan: emperor (Box 114)
  - Japan: population, emigration, labor (Box 114)
  - Shelley--Japanese ghost research (Box 114)
  - Japan: 1992 and later (Box 114)
  - Japanese in Latin America and other countries (Box 115)
  - War with Japan, medical experiments with POWs (Box 115)
  - Formosa (Box 115)
  - Japan: craftsmanship (Box 115)
  - Allied Press in Japan: Philippines Occupation and Korean War period, rosters (Box 115)
  - Japan: drama, art, culture (Box 115)
  - Haiti (Box 115)
  - Thailand (Box 115)
  - Oil in Asia--Seth (Box 115)
  - Peace Corps, Vista (Box 115)
  - TIME Inc. (Box 115)
  - Bahamas (Box 115)
  - Belgium (Box 115)
  - Britain, London (Box 115)
  - Bermuda (Box 115)
  - Canada (Box 115)
  - Chad (Box 115)
  - Corsica (Box 115)
  - Ethiopia (Box 115)
  - Falkland Islands (Box 115)
  - Florida (Box 115)
  - French Guiana and France (Box 115)
  - France (Box 115)
  - For LIFE: Fall of France, 500 words, World War Two, July 1989 (Box 115)
  - The Marquise de Polignac, Happening June 1940 (Box 115)
  - Germany (Box 115)
  - Gibraltar (Box 115)
  - Greenland (Box 115)
  - Hawaii (Box 115)
  - Iceland (Box 115)
  - Iran (Box 115)
  - Larchmont, Mamaroneck, New Rochelle, Westchester (Box 115)
  - Maine (Box 115)
  - Frenchboro Island, Maine (Box 115)
  - Pressmans, Barneys (Box 115)
  - Connecticut (Box 115)
  - Liechtenstein (Box 115)
  - Libya (Box 115)
  - Liberia (Box 115)
  - Long Island (Box 115)
  - Martha's Vineyard (Box 115)
  - Malta (Box 115)
  - Monte Carlo, Monaco (Box 115)
  - Nantucket, Block Island (Box 115)
  - Netherlands (Box 115)
  - Panama (Box 115)
  - New Orleans (Box 115)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 115)
  - Rhodesia (Box 116)
  - Sacramento (Box 116)
  - Sardinia (Box 116)
  - South Africa (Box 116)
  - Trieste (Box 116)
  - Photographers and Photography In My Life by Horace Bristol (Box 116)
  - Singapore: stories, clippings (Box 116)
  - Cavite, The Philippines (Box 116)
  - Singapore--Bangkok train story (Box 116)
  - Dorothy Danner, Santo Tomas (Box 116)
  - Malaysia (Box 116)
  - Lee Kuan Yew (Box 116)
  - U.S.S.R. (1 of 2) (Box 116)